RG004:142, Tolland Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Tolland Probate Court records
1830-1960
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Tolland District)
22.75 cubic feet
Record books, 1830-1920; Bond record books, 1867-1954; Probate files, 1830-1960.
RG004_142
1911-012, 1984, 005, 2010-037
Historical Note
Tolland, Tolland County, Town named 1715, Town established in May 1722
The Tolland Probate District was constituted June 4, 1830, from the Stafford Probate District. The Tolland Probate District merged with the Mansfield Probate District on January 5, 2011 to create the Mansfield - Tolland Probate District which serves the municipalities of Coventry, Mansfield, Tolland, and Willington.
Town of Tolland, Probate District chronology:
May 1715 - May 1759, Hartford District
May 1759 - June 3, 1830, Stafford District
June 4, 1830 - January 4, 2011, Tolland District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Mansfield - Tolland District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books volumes 1-12, 1830-1920; Bond record books, 1867-1954. Contact the probate court to access original record books afver volume 12. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1830-1960. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1830-1948 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books in accession 2010-037 are arranged numerically.
Probate files in accessions 1911-012 and 1974-005 are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1911-012 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the files in accession 1974-005.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Tolland
Places:
Tolland (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2010-037, Record books, 1830-1954, is stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files dated 1921 or later are RESTRICTED pending review by State Archives staff as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-12, 1830-1920; probate files, 1830-1880 (Accession 1911-012); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1911-012 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): October 14, 1911 (1830-1910); January 31, 1922, (1899-1912); December 7. 1933 (1888-1929; Pctober 25, 1935 (1878-1937); March 24, 1936 (1878-1937); September 2, 1936 (1878-1936); July 6, 1937 (1878-1937); March 25, 1938 (1931-1937); November 23, 1938 (1932-1938); May 9, 1939 (1932-1938); August 7, 1940 (1937-1939); October 14, 1941 (1923-1941); June 7, 1944 (1933-1942); April 30, 1945 (1939-1944); April 8, 1947 (1935-1946); September 22, 1949 (1935-1948); April 21, 1950 (1906-1948).There were interfiled into one alphbetic sequence.
The probate files in accession 1974-005 were transferred to the Connectictu State Library on November 27, 1974.
The record books in accesion 2010-037 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on May 11, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1920-1954; 7.5 cubic feet (15 volumes); 2010-037
  - Records, 1830-1838 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1838-1845 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1846-1849 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1849-1857 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1856-1863 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1863-1872 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1872-1880 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1880-1892 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1892-1902 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1902-1908 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1908-1915 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1915-1920 (Volume 12)
  - Bonds, 1867-1901 (Volume 1)
  - Bonds, 1900-1930 (Volume 2)
  - Bonds, 1928-1954 (Volume 3)
- Probate files, 1830-1948; 11.25 cubic feet; 1911-012
  - Abel - Balch (Drawer 1)
  - Baldwin - Binok (Drawer 2)
  - Bird - Bugbey, F. (Drawer 3)
  - Bugbey, G. - Chapman, M. (Drawer 4)
  - Chapman, N. - Cole (Drawer 5)
  - Comstock - Demead (Drawer 6)
  - Denman - Drake (Drawer 7)
  - Draper - Eldredge, E. (Drawer 8)
  - Eldridge, F. - Gaines (Drawer 9)
  - Galavin - Greene, N. (Drawer 10)
  - Greene, O. - Hall, A. (Drawer 11)
  - Hall, B.. - Hancock, G. (Drawer 12)
  - Hancock, H. - Herold, G. (Drawer 13)
  - Herold, H. - Hlobik, C. (Drawer 14)
  - Hlobik, D. - Hulett (Drawer 15)
  - Hull - Johnson, I. (Drawer 16)
  - Johnson, J. - Kempton (Drawer 17)
  - Kendall - Kwast (Drawer 18)
  - Labonte - Lillibridge, B. (Drawer 19)
  - Lillibridge, C. - Mardy (Drawer 20)
  - Marek - Morrison (Drawer 21)
  - Morse - Nowsch (Drawer 22)
  - Nye - Parizek (Drawer 23)
  - Parker - Potter, P. (Drawer 24)
  - Potter, Q. - Rider, D. (Drawer 25)
  - Rider, E. - Royce (Drawer 26)
  - Ruby - Slocum (Drawer 27)
  - Smith - Sparrow, J. (Drawer 28)
  - Sparrow, K.. - Sumner, J. (Drawer 29)
  - Sumner, K. - Underwood, F. (Drawer 30)
  - Underwood, G. - Webster, H. (Drawer 31)
  - Webster, I - Whitcomb (Drawer 32)
  - White - Winslow (Drawer 33)
  - Winter - Zusick; Miscellaneous (Drawer 34)
- Inventory Control Book, 1830-1948; T003073
  Index of the seventeen accessions of probate files merged into accession 1911-012
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, 1925-1960; 4 cubic feet; 1974-005
  - Amidon - Downes, Roy M. (Box 1)
  - Downes, Maud E. - Kocarnik (Box 2)
  - Kollar - Parod (Box 3)
  - Pease - Zuscik (Box 4)